Guide to the Don Sanders collection, 1960s-2015 MS 648
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Don Sanders collection
circa 1960s-2015
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Sanders, Don
MS 648
0.75 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
1.39 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0648aip_001 (1.39 GB)
6.70 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0648aip_002 (6.70 GB)
1.30 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0648aip_003 (1.3 GB)
This collection consists of digital and printed scans and copies from Don Sanders' scrapbooks.
Biographical / Historical
As a student at University of Houston, Don Sanders began writing and composing his own music in 1963. He eventually joined the growing folk scene at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. He has performed at Liberty Hall, Kerville Folk Festival, Sand Mountain Coffee House, the Old Quarter, the Grand 1894 Opera House, and Hofhienz Pavillion. Sanders started Mean N' Low Records in 1972 as a vehicle to release his own albums, a self-titled 12", "Extended Play," and "Limited Edition." He has also released the albums "El Mosquito in My Kitchen" (2006) and "Limelight" (2015). Throughout the 1970s and 1980s, he played clubs and at universities in Texas. He was a favorite at Texas A & M and was the influence for Lyle Lovett's "This Old Porch." Lovett even interview him for the school's newspaper. During this time, he began teaching music to children at the Gatesville School for Boys and elementary schools in the North Forest School District. He still performs and teaches music to children through workshops.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, images, news clippings, and other items chronicling the musical history of Don Sanders.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Don Sanders in February 2016.
Related Materials
Please see the Rice University KTRU Radio records, UA 011.
Accruals
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects
Music; Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Politics and government
Document Types
Folk music; Folk-rock music
Subjects (Persons)
Sanders, Don
Subjects (Corporations)
Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant
- Series I: Alphabetical files
  - Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - For the Sake of the Song: The Story of Anderson Fair notes, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lyrics, 1960s-1976, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - News Clippings, 1972-1978, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (printed scans), 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Promotional materials, 1970s, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Digital files
  - Scrapbook scans, 2016
    Scope and Contents
    The items in these files consist of scans from Don Sanders scrapbooks created by Woodson staff. There are master file tifs and access copy jpgs and pdfs.
  - Video oral history, 2017-03-21
    These born digital video files consist of one master copy mp4 and one access copy located at scholarship.rice.edu.
- Series III: Audio
  - Self-titled 12" LP, 1972 (Box 2)
    Conditions Governing Access
    These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: A1 - "Open My Third Eye," A2 - "Coffee Song," A3 - "Roaches," A4 - "Kent State History Play," A4 - "Anyone Who Must Leave Us," B1 - "Grunty Mind and the American Love Story"
  - "Extended Play" 12" LP, 1973 (Box 2)
    These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: A1 - "Heavy Word User," A2 - "Performance," A3 - "One Way Jesus," A4 - "Bruised Fruit"
  - "Limelight" (CD), 2015 (Box 2)
    These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Streets of Seville," "Until Victory," "Great Big Bottle," "New Gallows Farewell," "Mariner," "Limelight," "My Song," "Moment," "Disposable," "Vampire Bride," "Cutout Bin," "Quiet Day."